Royality meets reality.
Princess Protection Program is a family, tv movie,
comedy film directed by Allison Liddi-Brown.
When her nation is invaded, a young princess is taken
into the Princess Protection Program.
She is relocated to Louisiana, where she stays with a covert agent and his tomboyish
daughter, and must learn how to behave like an ordinary teenager.
Rosalinda María Montoya Fioré, played by Demi Lovato.
Carter Mason, played by Selena Gomez.
Ed, played by Nicholas Braun.
Joe Mason, played by Tom Verica.
The Director, played by Molly Hagan.
Brooke Angels, played by Samantha Droke.
Princess Protection Program is a 2009 American comedy film
released as a Disney Channel Original Movie.
It is directed by Allison Liddi-Brown and stars Demi Lovato and Selena Gomez.
The script was written by Annie DeYoung from a story
by Annie DeYoung and David Morgasen.
The film premiered on June 26, 2009, in the United States on Disney
Channel and was released on DVD on June 30, 2009.
The film won the 2009 Teen Choice Awards for Choice Summer Movie.
The film explores themes of princess, high school,
friendship, island, parent child relationship.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.